Norman H. Davis Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Norman H. Davis Papers 1898-1979 1915-1944
MSS17962
Davis, Norman H. (Norman Hezekiah), 1878-1944
44,000 items
99 containers plus 1 classified and 4 oversize
40.5 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Economist, diplomat and humanitarian. Correspondence, journals, minutes, speeches, statements, scrapbooks, memoranda, news clippings, printed matter, photographs, and other material relating mainly to Davis's participation between the world wars in international conferences on peace, disamament, and international monetary matters.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Davis, Norman H. (Norman Hezekiah), 1878-1944.; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964--Correspondence.; Lamont, Thomas W. (Thomas William), 1870-1948--Correspondence.; Vanderlip, Frank A. (Frank Arthur), 1864-1937--Correspondence.
Organizations
Allied and Associated Powers (1914-1920). Supreme Economic Council.; Conference for the Reduction and Limitation of Armaments (1932-1934: Geneva, Switzerland); International Economic Conference (1927: Geneva, Switzerland); League of Nations.; London Naval Conference (1935-1936: London, England); Monetary and Economic Conference (1933: London, England); Nine-Power Conference (1937: Brussels, Belgium); Paris Peace Conference (1919-1920)
Subjects
Arms control.; Disarmament.; International economic relations.; International relations.; Peace.; Security, International.; World War, 1914-1918--Peace.; World War, 1914-1918--Reparations.; World War, 1939-1945.
Occupations
Diplomats.; Economists.; Humanitarians.
Acquisition Information
The papers of Norman H. Davis, economist and diplomat, were given to the Library of Congress in 1953, 1958, 1964, and 1984 by the Council on Foreign Relations. Priscilla Kellert gave a further addition to the collection in 2007.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of Norman H. Davis are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Security Classified Documents
Government regulations control the use of security classified material in this collection. Manuscript Division staff can furnish information concerning access to and use of classified materials.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1978, Aug. 9 Born, Normandy, Bedford County, Tenn.
1897 1900 Attended Vanderbilt University, Nashville, Tenn., and Stanford University, Stanford, Calif.
1898 Married Mackie Paschall
1902 Began business career in Cuba
1905 1917 Organized Trust Co. of Cuba and served as president of the company
1917 Advisor on foreign loans to the secretary of the treasury
1918 Special delgate to Spain and representative of the United States Treasury in London, England and Paris, France
1919 Appointed finance commisioner of the United States to Europe American member, Armistice Commission Chairman of the finance section, Supreme Economic Council Financial advisor to Woodrow Wilson and the American Commission to Negotiate Peace Member of the Reparations and Financial Commissions Assistant secretary of the treasury
1920 Under secretary of state and acting secretary of state Chairman, Conference on International Communications, Washington, D. C.
1924 Chairman, League of Nations Commission to Determine the Status of Memel
1927 Member, American Delegation to the International Economic Conferrence, Geneva Switzerland Member, League of Nations Financial Committee
1932 Appointed member of of the organizing committee for the International Monetary and Economic Conference Chairman of the American delegation, Disarmament Conference, Geneva, Switzerland
1935 Head of the American delegation to the London Naval Conference
1937 United States delegate, Nine-Power Conference, Brussels, Belgium
1938 1944 Chairman, American Red Cross
1944, July 1 Died, Alexandria, Va.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of diplomat and economist Norman Hezekiah Davis (1878-1944) span the years 1898-1979 with the bulk of the material concentrated between 1915 and 1944. In 1902 Davis began his business career in Cuba where he organized the Trust Company of Cuba. He commenced a public career in 1917 and served in four presidential administrations consulting on international finance at the Department of Treasury, the Department of State, and international conferences and committees during World War I and the the interwar period. Davis was chairman of the of the American Red Cross from 1938 to his death in 1944.
The papers are organized into seven series: Correspondence and Other Papers, Printed Matter, Addition I, Addition II, Addition III, Oversize, and Classified. The Correspondence and Other Papers series consists of correspondence, diaries, journals, minutes, addresses, statements, scrapbooks, memoranda, clippings, printed matter, photographs, and other papers relating chiefly to Davis’s services as a participant in international conferences and commissions on peace, disarmament, monetary matters and as a financial and economic consultant. The series includes material on conferences and organizations including the Supreme Economic Council of the Allied and Associated Powers (1914-1920), the Armistice, Paris Peace Conference (1919), International Economic Conference (Geneva, 1927), League of Nations, Limitation of Arms Conference (Geneva, 1932-1934), Monetary and Economic Conference (London, 1933), London Naval Conference (1935-1936), the Brussels Nine-Power Conference (1937), and other conferences and organizations. Correspondents include Herbert Hoover, Viscount Robert Gascoyne-Cecil, Cecil of Chelwood, Cordell Hull, Thomas W. Lamont, and Frank A. Vanderlip.
Arrangement of the Papers
This collection is arranged in seven series:
Correspondence and Other Papers, 1916-1942
Printed Matter, 1933-1937
Addition I, 1915-1945
Addition II, 1918-1960
Addition III, 1898-1979
Oversize, 1920-1943
Classified, 1927-1935
Container List
- Correspondence and Other Papers, 1918-1942 (Box 1-71)
  Letters sent and received, memoranda, copies of statements and addresses, journals, minutes, addresses, statements, scrapbooks, memoranda, clippings, printed matter, photographs, and miscellaneous material.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of person, organization, or subject. There is some arrangement of dossiers within larger subjects such as the Supreme Economic Council, but many subject groups are wholly unarranged.
  - "A" cross-reference sheets (Box 1)
  - "A" miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Adams, Mary, 1938-1942 (Box 1)
  - Aircraft protocol, 1937 (Box 1)
  - "An" miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - American Council, Institute of Pacific Relations, 1928-1939 (Box 1)
  - American Council of St. Luke's International Medical Centre, 1938-1940 (Box 1)
  - American Red Cross See Container 48, Red Cross (Box 1)
  - Armistice (Box 1)
    - Terms of armistice, 1918, Nov. 11 (Box 1)
    - Additional armistice terms, 1918, Dec. 17 (Box 1)
    - Armistice agreements, 1918-1919 (Box 1)
    - Terms of the armistice agreements, 1918-1919 (Box 1)
    - Spa, Belgium, 1919 (Box 1)
    - Spa., Belgium, Strauss's file on Spa meeting, 1919 (Box 1)
  - Arms embargo - neutrality legislation, 1935, Apr.-Oct. (Box 2)
  - Arms manufacture - miscellaneous memoranda and correspondence, 1934-1935 (Box 2)
  - Armstrong, Hamilton Fish, 1926-1942 (Box 2)
  - Astor, Vicount, 1936-1942 (Box 2)
  - Atherton, Ray, 1932-1942 (Box 2)
  - "B" cross-reference sheets (Box 2)
  - "B" miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Baker, Newton Diehl, 1922-1933 (Box 3)
  - Baker, Ray Stannard, 1922-1935 (Box 3)
  - Baruch, Bernard M., 1920-1935 (Box 3)
  - Belgium, 1919 (Box 3)
  - Berle, A. A., Jr., 1938 (Box 3)
  - Bingham, Robert Worth, 1933-1941 (Box 3)
  - "Bo" miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Bolivia, 1919 (Box 3)
  - Bowker, R. R., 1922-1932 (Box 3)
  - "Br" miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Breese, William, 1939 (Box 3)
  - Brussels Conference (Box 4)
    - Memoranda and cables, 1937, Mar.-June (Box 4)
    - Confidential correspondence, 1937, Aug-Nov. (Box 4)
    - Nine-Power Conference, 1937, Oct.-Nov., (2 folders) (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous clippings, 1937, Oct.-Nov. (Box 4)
    - Conversations and memoranda, 1937, Oct.-Dec. (Box 4)
    - Telegrams, 1937, Oct.-1938, Jan. (Box 4)
    - Acts of the conference, 1937, Nov. (Box 5)
    - Drafts and reports, 1937, Nov. (Box 5)
    - Meeting, 1937, Nov., (3 folders) (Box 5)
    - Press statement, 1937, Dec. 11 (Box 5)
    - Davis's official report, 1937, Dec. 16 (Box 5)
    - Map of China, land and population, undated (Box 5)
  - Bullard, Arthur, 1921-1929 (Box 6)
  - Bullard, Mrs. Arthur, 1930-1936 (Box 6)
  - Burnett, Philip M., 1938-1939 (Box 6)
  - "C" cross-reference sheets (Box 6)
  - "C" miscellaneous (Box 6)
  - Campaign, 1924, (1 folder); (4 folders) (Box 6, Box 7)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace and Carnegie Corp. (Box 7)
    - 1933-1937, (3 folders) (Box 7)
    - 1938-1942, (2 folders) (Box 8)
  - Castle, William R., 1929-1932 (Box 8)
  - Cecil, Vicount, 1924-1938 (Box 8)
  - Century Association, 1934-1942 (Box 8)
  - Chamberlain, Neville, 1937, June-July (Box 8)
  - "C" miscellaneous (Box 8)
  - Colby, Bainbridge, 1920 (Box 8)
  - Committee on Economic Sanctions, 1931 (Box 8)
  - Conversations, memoranda of 1920-1935, (6 folders) (Box 9)
  - "Cor" miscellaneous (Box 9)
  - Council on Foreign Bondholders, 1932-1934 (Box 9)
  - Council on Foreign Relations (Box 9)
    - 1933-1935 (Box 9)
    - 1936-1937, (2 folders) (Box 10)
  - Cox, James M., 1920-1921 (Box 10)
  - Cravath, Paul D., regarding his Council on Foreign Relations address, 1920-1922 (Box 10)
  - Crosby, Oscar T., 1919 (Box 10)
  - Czechoslovakia, 1919 (Box 10)
  - 'D" cross-reference sheets (Box 10)
  - "D" miscellaneous (Box 10)
  - Davis, John W., 1921-1942 (Box 10)
  - Davis, Edwin L., 1919-1920 (Box 10)
  - Davis, Norman H. (Box 11)
    - Family and personal letters, 1918-1921 (Box 11)
    - Official and semiofficial correspondence, 1918-1921 (Box 11)
    - Personal and semiofficial correspondence, 1918-1921 (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1919-1925 (Box 11)
    - Letters of congratulation, 1919-1932 (Box 11)
    - Congratulatory letters of appointment as under secretary of state, 1921 (Box 11)
    - Telegrams, 1932, Oct.-Dec. (Box 11)
      - Sent, (2 folders) (Box 11)
      - Received (Box 11)
    - Personal, London, England and Geneva, Switzerland, correspondence, 1932, Oct.-Dec. (Box 11)
    - Telegrams sent, 1932, Nov. (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1933-1934, (6 folders) (Box 12)
    - Official correspondence, 1934-1935, (2 folders) (Box 12)
    - Financial expenses, 1933 (Box 12)
    - Family letters, mainly, 1918-1921 (Box 13)
    - Personal correspondence, 1938-1942 (Box 13)
      - A-L, mainly, (3 folders) (Box 13)
      - M-W, mainly, (2 folders) (Box 14)
      - Stockbridge House (Wenzel Krebs), circa 1938-1942 (Box 14)
    - Davis, Mackie Paschall (wife), mainly, 1938-1942 (Box 14)
    - Financial, personal receipted bills (Box 14)
    - Personal miscellany, 1919-1933 (Box 14)
    - Personal bills and receipts, 1933 (Box 15)
    - Personal, salary, expenses, etc., 1934-1937 (Box 15)
    - Statements for publication, 1919 (Box 15)
    - Speeches and articles, 1919-1923 (Box 15)
    - Address before Council on Foreign Relations and related correspondence, 1922, Feb. 17 (Box 15)
    - Addresses and articles (Box 15)
      - 1923-1930, (2 folders) (Box 15)
      - 1925-1934 (Box 16)
    - Press relating to Brussels conference an other Statements, 1932-1937 (Box 16)
    - Addresses and articles, 1935-1940 (Box 16)
    - Davis address notes, undated (Box 16)
    - Desk diaries, 1919-1921, 1932 (Box 16)
    - Diary and memoranda of conversations, 1932, Jan.-Aug. (Box 16)
    - Degree from Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass., 1935 (Box 17)
    - Miscellaneous, 1937 (Box 17)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 17)
  - Davis, Paul M. 1921 (Box 17)
  - Disarmament (Conference for the Reduction and Limitation of Armaments, Geneva, Switzerland) (Box 17)
    - Preparatory Commission, 1930, Nov.-Dec. (Box 17)
    - Draft convention and analysis, circa 1931 Nov. (Box 17)
    - Minutes and memoranda on department meetings, 1931, Nov.-1932, Jan. (Box 17)
    - Draft convention, circa 1931, Dec. (Box 17)
    - Congratulatory Letters to Davis, 1931, Dec.-1932, Jan. (Box 17)
    - Pre-conference papers, 1931, Dec.-1932, Jan. (Box 17)
    - Correspondence, 1931, Dec.-1932, Feb. (Box 17)
    - Position of Armament in Various Countries, 1931, Dec.-1932, July (Box 17)
    - Air Commission Memoranda, Jan.-May 1932, Jan-May (Box 17)
    - Confidential memoranda, 1932, Jan.-Nov. (Box 17)
    - Correspondence, 1932, Jan.-Dec. (Box 18)
    - Minutes of conference, 1932, Feb. (Box 18)
    - National Defense Expenditure Commission, 1932, Feb.-May (Box 18)
    - Naval Commission, 1932, Feb.-June (Box 18)
    - Correspondence and memoranda, 1932, Feb.-July (Box 18)
    - Documents, 1st Session, 1932, Feb.-July (Box 18)
    - Miscellaneous documents, 1932, Feb.-Dec. (Box 18)
    - Proposals of delegations, 1932, Feb.-1933, Jan. (Box 18)
    - State Department, press releases (Box 18)
      - 1932, Feb.-1933, Dec. (Box 18)
      - 1932, Feb.-1933, Dec. (Box 19)
    - Appointment of Norman H. Davis, 1932, Mar. 9 (Box 19)
    - General Commission, 1932, Mar.-July (Box 19)
    - Journal, 1932, Feb.-July, (2 folders) (Box 19)
    - Trip to United States by Davis, 1932, Mar. (Box 20)
    - Trans-Atlantic telephone conversations, 1932, June-July (Box 20)
    - Draft resolutions, 1932, June-July (Box 20)
    - Documents, 1932, June-Dec. (Box 20)
    - Conclusions of preparatory commission, 1932, Aug. (Box 20)
    - Cables, 1932, Oct.-Dec. (Box 20)
    - Naval memoranda, 1932,Oct-1934, June (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous documents, 1932, Nov.-1933,Oct. (Box 21)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1932, Nov.-1934, Jan. (Box 21)
    - Five-Power conversations, 1932, Dec. (Box 21)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 21)
      - 1932 Nov.-1934 Jan. (Box 21)
      - 1933 Feb.-June (Box 21)
    - General commission, 1933, Feb.-June, (2 folders) (Box 21)
    - State Department memoranda, Mar.-June 1933, Mar.-June (Box 21)
    - Memoranda, 1933, Mar.-July (Box 22)
    - Four-Power Pact, 1933, Apr.-May (Box 22)
    - Press conferences and notes, 1933, Apr.-June (Box 22)
    - Correspondence and memoranda, 1933, May (Box 22)
    - Memoranda, 1933, July-Sept. (Box 22)
    - Press conferences, 1933, Sept.-Oct. (Box 22)
    - Memoranda on conversations, 1933, Sept.-Nov. (Box 22)
    - Miscellaneous documents, 1933 Sept.-1934, Feb. (Box 22)
    - French, German, and British notes, Oct. 1933, Oct.-1934, Dec. (Box 22)
    - Mainly correspondence, 1933, Dec.-1934, Feb. (Box 23)
    - Miscellaneous, 1934, Feb.-Sept. (Box 23)
    - Resolutions, 1934, June (Box 23)
    - Cables, Geneva, Switzerland, 1935, Jan.-Sept. (Box 23)
    - Cables Sent - Geneva, Switzerland, 1935, Jan.-Sept. (Box 23)
    - Miscellaneous data, 1934-1935 (Box 23)
    - General disarmament and security negotiations, 1933-1940, (2 folders) (Box 23)
  - Dulles, Allen W., 1921-1941 (Box 23)
  - Dunn, James C., 1932-1936 (Box 24)
  - "E" cross reference sheets (Box 24)
  - "E" miscellaneous (Box 24)
  - European situations (Box 24)
    - Miscellaneous cables and memoranda, 1935, Apr.-May (Box 24)
    - Telegrams received, 1935, Apr.-May (Box 24)
    - Current and miscellaneous dispatches, 1935, Jan. -Mar. (Box 24)
    - Memoranda, 1937, Jan.-Mar. (Box 24)
  - "F" cross-reference sheets (Box 25)
  - "Fa-Fi" miscellaneous (Box 25)
  - Fitzgerald, C. C., 1938-1939 (Box 25)
  - Fleming, D. F., 1928-1942 (Box 25)
  - "Fo-Fu" miscellaneous (Box 25)
  - Foreign Policy Association, 1923-1942, (3 folders) (Box 25)
  - Fortune, 1937-1942 (Box 26)
  - France (Box 26)
    - Relief to, 1941 (Box 26)
    - Embassy in United States., 1920-1921 (Box 26)
    - Minister of Finance, 1920 (Box 26)
  - Franklin Institute, Philadelphia, Pa. 1938 (Box 26)
  - "G" cross reference sheets (Box 26)
  - "G" miscellaneous (Box 26)
  - Gibson, Hugh S., 1920-1938 (Box 26)
  - Glass, Carter, 1922-1940 (Box 26)
  - Great Britain, embassy in United States, 1920 (Box 26)
  - Green, Joseph C. arms embargo correspondence, 1935 (Box 26)
  - Grew, Joseph C., 1919 (Box 26)
  - Guaranty Trust Co., 1919-1921 (Box 26)
  - 'H" cross reference sheets (Box 26)
  - "H" miscellaneous (Box 26)
  - Harding, Warren G., 1921, Mar. 8 (Box 27)
  - Harrison, Pat, 1928-1929 (Box 27)
  - Hill, Robert C., 1919-1942 (Box 27)
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1919-1933 (Box 27)
  - Hornbeck, Stanley K., 1936-1937 (Box 27)
  - Hughes, Charles Evans, 1921 (Box 27)
  - Hull, Cordell, 1921-1942, (2 folders) (Box 27)
  - "I" miscellaneous (Box 28)
  - Institute of Politics, Williams College, Williamstown, Mass. 1921-1930, (2 folders) (Box 28)
  - International Chamber of Commerce (Box 28)
    - Minutes, agenda, and other material, 1928-1929 (Box 28)
    - Miscellany, 1928-1932 (Box 28)
    - Information Service, 1928-1930 (Box 29)
    - Special reports, 1928-1930 (Box 29)
    - Committee statement, 1931 (Box 29)
  - International Communications Conference (Box 29)
    - General, 1919-20, (2 folders) (Box 29)
    - Subcommittee on German cables, 1920, Oct.-1921, Mar., (4 folders) (Box 30)
    - Plenary session and plenary conference, 1920 (Box 30)
  - International Conference on Customs, 1923 (Box 31)
  - International Economic Conference, Geneva, Switzerland, 1927 (Box 31)
    - Chronological file, (4 folders) (Box 31)
    - Commerce (Box 32)
    - Journal (Box 32)
    - Miscellany (Box 32)
    - Closing speech (Box 32)
  - Italy, financial representative, 1920-1921 (Box 32)
  - 'J" cross reference sheets (Box 32)
  - J "miscellaneous" (Box 32)
  - Japan (Box 32)
    - Embassy in United States, 1920-1921 (Box 32)
    - Cables, 1920-1921 (Box 32)
    - Embassy in U.S. (Baron Shidehara), 1922 (Box 32)
  - Jay, N. Dean, regarding Austrian loan, 1932 (Box 32)
  - Jones, R. E., 1920 (Box 32)
  - "K" cross-reference sheets (Box 32)
  - "K" miscellaneous (Box 32)
  - Kennedy, Joseph P., 1922-1938 (Box 32)
  - Keynes, J. M., 1920 (Box 32)
  - Hungary finance minister, Baron Koranyi, 1932 (Box 32)
  - "L" cross-reference sheets (Box 33)
  - "L" miscellaneous (Box 33)
  - Lamont, Thomas W., (2 folders) (Box 33)
  - League of Nations (Box 33)
    - Taft, William H., speech (Box 33)
    - Miscellany, 1919-1940 (Box 33)
    - Mandates, 1921 (Box 33)
    - Sheppard, Morris, speech, 1923 (Box 33)
    - Miscellany, 1923 (Box 33)
    - Protocol on arbitration, 1924 (Box 33)
    - Letters of congratulation, 1931 (Box 33)
    - Financial committee (Box 33)
      - Danzig, 1931 (Box 33)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1931-1932 (Box 34)
      - Gold delegation, 1931-1932 (Box 34)
      - Chronological file, 1931-1937, (2 folders) (Box 34)
      - Austria, 1932 (Box 34)
      - Bulgaria, 1932 (Box 34)
      - Estonia, 1932 (Box 34)
      - Greece, 1932 (Box 34)
      - Hungary, 1932 (Box 34)
      - Romania, 1932 (Box 34)
    - Chinese government, 1932 (Box 35)
    - Loan Committee, 1932 (Box 35)
  - League of Nations Association, 1928-1942 (Box 35)
  - Lippmann, Walter, 1931-1942 (Box 35)
  - London Naval Conference (Box 35)
    - Chronological file, 1934-1937 (Box 35)
    - London Naval Treaty of 1930 (Box 35)
    - Naval memoranda, 1934, Mar.-Oct. (Box 35)
    - British-United States meeting minutes, 1934, June-July and Oct. (Box 35)
    - Draft for final statements, 1934, July (Box 35)
    - Memoranda of meetings and minutes, 1934, Oct.-Dec. (Box 36)
    - Miscellaneous memoranda, 1934, Oct.-Dec. (Box 36)
    - Telegrams received, naval, 1935, Jan.-Aug. (Box 36)
    - Naval memoranda, 1935, Jan.-Nov. (Box 36)
    - Telegrams sent, naval, 1935, Mar.-Nov. (Box 36)
    - Anglo-German Naval Agreement, 1935, June (Box 36)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1935, Oct.-Dec. (Box 36)
    - American position, statements, 1935, Nov. (Box 36)
    - Accounts and travel orders, 1935, Nov. -1936, Mar. (Box 36)
    - Naval Conference, opening speech, 1935, Dec. (Box 37)
    - Conversation memoranda, 1935, Dec.-1936, Jan. (Box 37)
    - Naval memoranda, 1935, Dec.-1936, Mar. (Box 37)
    - Documents, 1935, Dec.-1936, Mar. (Box 37)
    - Official correspondence, 1935, Dec.-1936, Mar. (Box 37)
    - Minutes, 1st Committee, 1935, Dec.-1936, Mar. (Box 37)
    - Miscellaneous documents, Dec. 1935, Dec.-1936, Apr. (Box 37)
    - Subcommittee (Advance Notification), 1936, Jan. (Box 38)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1936, Jan.-Mar. (Box 38)
    - Subcommittee (Qualitative Limitation), 1936, Feb. (Box 38)
    - Subcommittee (Definitions), 1936, Feb. (Box 38)
    - Qualitative Subcommittee, 1936, Feb. (Box 38)
    - Subcommittee (Qualitative Limitation) (Box 38)
    - London Naval Treaty of 1936, 1936, Mar. (Box 39)
    - Drafting Committee, 1936, Mar. (Box 39)
    - Second plenary session, 1936, Mar. (Box 39)
    - Naval Conference, speech by Davis, final session, 1936, Mar. (Box 39)
    - Naval cables and memoranda, 1936, Apr.-Nov. (Box 39)
    - Naval Conferences, Senate hearings, 1936, May (Box 39)
  - Long, Boas W., 1920-1921 (Box 40)
  - Lothian, Marquis of, 1928-1942, (2 folders) (Box 40)
  - Loveday, A., 1931-1932 (Box 40)
  - "M" crossreference sheets (Box 40)
  - "M" miscellaneous, material relating to the Philippine problem, and various dispatches relating to May 1935 Hitler speech, 1935, undated (Box 40)
  - "Mc" miscellaneous (Box 40)
  - McAdoo, William G., 1920-1927 (Box 40)
  - MacDonald, J. Ramsay, 1923-1932 (Box 40)
  - Memel, Territory of, letters to Bullard, etc. (Box 40)
    - 1922-1930 (Box 40)
    - 1924-1927, (2 folders) (Box 41)
  - Metropolitan Club, Washington, D. C., 1920-1939 (Box 41)
  - Mexico, embassy in U.S., 1920 (Box 41)
  - Mexico oil controversy, 1920 (Box 41)
  - Moffat, J. Pierrepont, 1932-1941, (2 folders) (Box 41)
  - Monetary and Economic Conference, London, England (Box 41)
    - China and India, 1932 (Box 41)
    - Miscellaneous, 1932 (Box 41)
    - 1932-1933 (2 folders) (Box 42)
    - Documents, 1932-1933 (Box 42)
    - 1933, (3 folders) (Box 42)
    - Wheat, 1933 (Box 42)
  - Morgan, Edwin, 1921 (Box 42)
  - Morris, Roland, 1921-1927 (Box 42)
  - "N" cross reference sheets (Box 43)
  - "N" miscellaneous (Box 43)
  - National Advisory Council on Radio in Education, 1930-1932 (Box 43)
  - Naval matters See Containers 35-39, London Naval Conference (Box 43)
  - Neutrality, 1933-1937, (3 folders) (Box 43)
  - New York World, 1922-1924 (Box 43)
  - "O" cross-reference sheets (Box 43)
  - "O" miscellaneous (Box 43)
  - P cross reference sheets (Box 43)
  - "P" miscellaneous (Box 43)
  - Paris Peace Conference (Box 43)
    - Germany, 1919 (Box 43)
    - German Documents, 1919 (Box 43)
    - Germany, minutes of sub-committee, mainly 1919 (2 folders) (Box 44)
    - German Financial Commission, 1919 (Box 44)
    - Germany, reports of Economic Conference, Spa, Belgium, 1919 (Box 44)
    - Notes concerning meeting with Germans at Spa, Belgium, 1919, Mar. 4 (Box 44)
    - Versailles Treaty data, 1919-1920 (Box 44)
    - Austria, 1918-1919 (Box 45)
    - Austrian notes, 1919 (Box 45)
    - Conditions of peace with Austria, 1919, (2 folders) (Box 45)
    - Reparations, German, 1919 (Box 45)
    - Reparations clauses, treaty with Germany, 1919 (Box 45)
    - Reparations, Austria, 1919 (Box 46)
    - Reparations, Bulgaria, 1919 (Box 46)
    - Reparation of Damages, Commission meetings, minutes, 1919 (Box 46)
    - Reconstruction, 1919 (Box 46)
    - Financial reconstruction, 1919-1920 (Box 46)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 46)